Welcome to OpenClaw Installation Tutorial.
In this video, we'll install OpenClaw on
DigitalOcean step by step.
Step 1: Go to digitalocean.com and click
Sign Up. Enter your email and create a
or
or GitHub.
Step 2: Verify your email. Open your inbox
and click the verification link from
DigitalOcean.
Step 3: Add a payment method. Click
Billing, then Payment Methods, then Add
connect
connect PayPal.
The basic server costs $6 per month. You
can cancel anytime.
Step 4: Create a droplet. Click the green
Create button in the top right, then
select Droplets from the menu.
Step 5: Choose Ubuntu 22.04 LTS as your
operating system. LTS means Long Term
Support - the most stable version.
Step 6: Select the 12 dollar per month
plan with 2 GB RAM, 1 CPU, and 50 GB SSD.
This gives you room for multiple agents.
Step 7: Choose a data center close to you.
Europe: London or Frankfurt. USA: New York
or San Francisco.
Step 8: Select Password authentication and
create a strong password. Write it down
somewhere safe!
Step 9: Name your droplet. Use something
memorable like openclaw-bot or
my-ai-assistant.
Step 10: Click Create Droplet and wait 30
to 60 seconds while it sets up.
Step 11: Copy your server's IP address. It
looks like 138.68.161.145. Click the copy
icon.
Step 12: Open Terminal on Mac or Command
Prompt on Windows. Type: ssh root@ then
paste your IP address.
Step 13: Type yes when asked about
fingerprint, then enter your password. You
won't see characters as you type.
Step 14: Update system packages. Run: apt
update && apt upgrade -y. Wait 1 to 3
minutes.
Step 15: Install Node.js. Run: curl -fsSL
https://deb.nodesource.com/setup_20.x |
bash - then apt install -y nodejs
Step 16: Verify Node installation. Run:
node --version. You should see v20.x.x
Step 17: Install OpenClaw. Run: npm
install -g openclaw. Wait 1 to 2 minutes
for installation.
Step 18: Start OpenClaw setup. Run:
openclaw gateway start. You'll be asked
several configuration questions.
Choose anthropic as your model provider
and enter your Anthropic API key from
console.anthropic.com
Step 19: Connect WhatsApp. A QR code will
appear. Open WhatsApp on your phone, tap
a
a Device.
Scan the QR code on your computer screen
and wait for the Connected message.
Congratulations! OpenClaw is now running
24/7. Send a WhatsApp message to test your
AI assistant.
For help and documentation, visit
openclaw.ai or join the Discord community.
Thanks for watching!